All right. Um, welcome back. So, in this
video, we're going to talk about the
turnary operator. Before I show you
that, I thought it'd be helpful to
review how an if statement works. And
one of the ways I thought would be
helpful to do that, let's do it in
Excel. Hopefully, you're familiar with
Excel. If you're not, here's a free
lesson. Um, so what you'll do, um, let's
say we want to compare price A to price
B and then determine which column is
bigger. The way we can do this is we can
use an if statement in Excel. The way
you do that is you say equals if and
then in parenthesis it says let you need
to give it a logical test first. So what
we'll do is we'll say if cell A2 is
bigger then or equal to B2 then we'll
put a comma and then it'll say what
value do you want to appear in this cell
if this condition is true? We'll say A.
And if it's not true we'll say B. Now,
if I hit enter, A2 is bigger than B2.
So, it's going to return A. So, if I hit
enter, it's A. If I copy this down to
the next line, A3 is bigger than or
equal to B3, and so it returns A.
However, if I copy this to the next
line,
A4 is not bigger than B4, and so instead
of returning A, it returns B. The reason
I showed you this is this is very
similar to how the turnary operator
works in JavaScript. So we're going to
go over to Visual Studio Code and I'm
going to clear out a lot of the code
that we wrote last time.
So what we can do is we can say if we
want to use a turnary operator, the
turnary operator works very much like
that Excel if statement. So we can
create a variable. We'll say let my
variable
equal.
And so just like we did equals if
something for um a condition to check
and then what to put if it's true and
what to put if it's false.
We'll do a very similar thing here. So
we'll say my variable equals
let's do 10 is greater than five
and then we'll put the question mark.
That's the turnary operator. So we're
saying if 10 is bigger than five then we
want the value of my variable to be um
first and then we'll put a colon and
then we'll say otherwise we want the
value to be second.
So what this does is it says set my
variable equal to either first or
second. If 10 is bigger than five, set
it to first. If 10 is not bigger than
five, set it to second.
So coming back over to Excel, it's
similar to how we said if 10 is bigger
than five, set it to A. If 10 is not
bigger than 5, set it to B. So if we
wanted to duplicate that, we'd say if 10
is greater than or equal to 5, question
mark. And this is what comes out if it's
true. So we'd put A. This is what comes
out if it's false. We'd put B. To show
you this in action, I'll alert my
variable. We'll save that. So we're
saying if 10 is bigger than five, set my
variable to A. If 10 is not bigger than
five, set my variable to B. So we'll
save and
we'll go live.
And we get a just like we would have
expected.
Um, if we do 40 and 50 and save and we
go live, we get B.
So hopefully that helps you understand a
little bit about how the turnary
operator works. It's very similar to the
ifs um if function in Excel um where you
take a condition, you put a question
mark, what you put after the question
mark is what will happen if it's true.
What you put after the colon is what
will happen if it's false. And that is
the turnary operator.